The experiments we've run so far
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
これまでの実験の結果からして―
prove that the D-mails are being sent to the past.
Ｄメールは過去に
送られていることが実証された
But I couldn't change the outcome of my match with Feyris!
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）
でもフェイリスたんとの
勝負の結果は―
改変できなかったお
That's a problem with you, not with the D-mail.
それは お前自身の問題だ
There are problems with the system, including the issue with Rukako,
ま… るか子の件も含め―
精度には問題があるが―
but if we work on it, we can build a real time machine...
改良すれば
本物のタイムマシンが
（フェイリス）タイムマシン？
Time machine?
おっ
You were listening to us?
盗み聞きか？
Feyris just brought your order!
フェイリスは ご注文を
お持ちしただけニャン
Do you want any maple syrup or milk?
ガムシロとミルクは
入れますかニャ？
断る！
I refuse!
Then you can have my everything!
（フェイリス）そんな凶真(きょうま)には
全部 入れちゃうニャ
（フェイリス）ニャンニャン
There it is!
（橋田）出たー！
秘技！ 目を見て混ぜ混ぜ
Secret Move: Stir While Gazing Into Their Eyes!
I'm so jealous I could explode, Okarin.
うらやましす オカリン
Kyouma, what do you mean by a time machine?
凶真　タイムマシンって
何のことかニャ？
Do you think you can seduce me into giving up classified information?
そんな色仕掛けで
機密事項を漏らすとでも？
I won't ask Kyouma then.
凶真には聞かないニャ
Daru-meow!
ダルニャーン
（岡部）フッ ダルが俺を裏切る…
（橋田）過去にメールを送れる―
You think Daru would betray me?
We built a machine that sends texts to the past,
（橋田）
マシンを作ったお　主に僕が
and by "we," I mean mostly me!
That was entirely too fast!
（岡部）秒殺にも程がある！
Messages to the past?
過去に メールを？
Chaos Theory
Homeostasis
～
Stupid Daru...
（岡部）ダルのやつ
部外者に秘密事項を…
spreading our secrets to outsiders...
Why?
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）どうして？
どうして
そういうふうに取るの？
Why must you take it that way?
I just wanted to...
（紅莉栖）私は ただ…
No, that's not what I meant!
違う！ そんなつもりじゃ…
I...
私は… ハッ
（岡部）ん？
あっ おお…
（岡部）あ…
Wh-Wh-What?
なな… な なんだ？
I'm not crying!
（紅莉栖）泣いてない
（岡部）あ？
It's not like I was crying, okay?
（紅莉栖）
別に泣いてなんてないから
なっ うう…
どう見ても泣いてただろ？
You were clearly crying...
Your eyes are still red.
まだ目が赤いぞ
（紅莉栖）ハッ
No way!
ちっ 違う
これは目にゴミが
Something's in my eye...
お前は昭和のドラマか？
What is this, an old soap opera?
（紅莉栖）ううっ…
と… とにかく泣いてない！
Anyway, I'm not crying,
so no questions.
だから追求しないこと
分かった？
Got it?
I didn't say anything.
別に追求するとは
ひと言も言ってない
（紅莉栖）う… うるさい！
Shut up!
（岡部）え？
おお…
ハア…
（紅莉栖）うっ…
（岡部）え？
（紅莉栖）う… うっ
（岡部）ん…
ハア…
クリスティーナ
Christin—
Shut up! Don't talk to me!
（紅莉栖）
うっさい 話しかけるな！
（岡部）フン…
I'll just say this...
これだけは言っておく
You're an important ally.
お前は大切な仲間だ
Any time you want to talk, I'll listen.
相談には いつでも乗る
Okabe...
岡部
（岡部）フッフフフ
Just as planned, she fell for it!
計画どおり
コロリとワナにはまったぞ！
ああ これで徹底的に
こき使えるというものだ
Now I can use her for all the grunt work!
ハアッ ハハハ…
おい
Hey.
Good work out there!
（フェイリス）お疲れさまニャー
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）
ああ フェリスちゃん
Feyris!
Are you heading to Kyouma's?
これから凶真の所かニャ？
Yeah, he wanted me to bring lunch.
（まゆり）うん
お昼ごはんを買ってきてって
（フェイリス）ふーん
Hey, have you seen the time machine, Mayushii?
ねえ  まゆしぃは
見たことあるニャ？
タイムマシン
ん？ タイム…
Time...
Oh, the Phone Microwave?
ああ！ 電話レンジさん？
Phone Microwave?
（フェイリス）電話レンジ？
There's this big sparky thing, and it's kind of scary...
バチバチって雷みたいのが―
こう ビリビリーって
ちょっと怖いんだあ
Wow!
すっごいニャ
It's like a time machine out of the movies.
映画に出てくる
タイムマシンみたいニャ
Yeah...
うん…
But Mayushii doesn't really want him doing that stuff.
でも まゆしぃは―
あんまり ああいうこと
してほしくないんだけどなあ
Why?
どうしてニャン？
うーん なんか…
It feels like Okarin is leaving me.
オカリンが遠くに行っちゃう
感じがするのです
We will now begin our Round—
（岡部）
では これより円卓会議を…
（橋田）オカリン オカリン
Okarin! Okarin!
なんだ！
What?
Isn't this strange?
おかしくね？
Mayushii says she isn't cosplaying.
まゆ氏は自分では
コスプレしないと言ってたお？
It isn't cosplay.
コスプレではない
学校の制服だ
It's her school uniform.
I had school today.
今日 登校日だったんだ
It's a super-realistic portrayal of a school uniform.
学校の制服…
むお… 完成度激高
That's sexual harassment, and she doesn't have to put up with it.
“完成度”とか言うの
普通にセクハラだから
Here's yours, Okarin!
はい オカリンの分
Thanks.
ああ… って違う！
No, wait. I said we're having a Round Table!
“円卓会議”だと
言ってるだろうが
You're the one who wanted me to bring lunch.
“お昼 買ってきて”って
言ったのはオカリンだよ
（紅莉栖）
気にしなくていいわよ
Don't mind him.
どうせ大した話じゃ
ないんだから
Obviously, it isn't anything important.
You can say that after you hear the discussion topic...
（岡部）それは今日の議題を
聞いてからにしてもらおう
Physical time travel!
ズバリ
物理的タイムトラベルだ！
Mayuri, is there still barley tea in the fridge?
まゆり
麦茶 冷蔵庫に まだある？
One second.
（まゆり）ちょっと待っててね
Realistic.
完成度高…
It's me!
（岡部）俺だ　機関による―
The Organization has initiated an operation to tear apart the lab.
ラボ内の切り崩し工作が
始まったようだ
Hououin Kyouma's words, my words,
この鳳凰院(ほうおういん)凶真の言葉が
ラボメンの心に届かないのだ！
fail to reach them!
Do they ever?
（橋田）それ前からじゃね？
Then why are you ignoring my awesome topic?
ならなぜ この
すばらしい議題を―
華麗にスルーするのだ！
Because it's impossible.
（紅莉栖）
無理に決まっているからでしょ
We can send messages to the past.
メールは過去に送られているのだ
可能性は…
It must be possible...
It's not.
（紅莉栖）ない！
（岡部）ああ…
We can send 36 bytes plus some extra.
送れるのは
36バイト プラスアルファ
Three messages, each with six characters.
６文字 掛ける３通
それ以上は無理
No more.
If you want to experiment, why not be the guinea pig?
試したければ
自分 使って実験してみれば？
That's if you don't mind ending up as a gel-Okarin.
ゲルオカリンになっても
よければ
Gel-Okarin, huh?
（まゆり）ゲルオカリンかあ…
That'd really hurt.
（橋田）イタすぎ
（紅莉栖）
物理的タイムトラベルの
難しさは―
SERN's experiments demonstrate the difficulties
inherent to physical time travel.
ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)の実験が証明している
Even using the LHC, the largest particle accelerator in the world,
世界最大のＬＨＣを使っても
成し遂げていないのよ
they've had no success.
We can't possibly do it with this equipment.
こんな設備でできるわけない
Then how do the messages get to the past?
ならなぜ
メールは送られている？
I don't know.
分からない
That's the problem.
それが問題なの
As I said before,
前にも言ったように―
SERN's trying to use the lifter-black hole combination
ＳＥＲＮはブラックホールと
リフターの力で―
to achieve time travel.
タイムトラベルを
可能にしようとしている
The Phone Microwave probably works on the same principle.
この電話レンジも
恐らく原理は同じ
But the microwave doesn't have anything
なのに―
リフターに相当するものは
レンジの中にはない
to function as a lifter.
So where is it?
（岡部）どこにある？
I don't know.
さあね
We're limited in the times we can send D-mail too.
Ｄメールが送れる時間も
まだ限られているし
Currently, we can't be sure that this machine
現状では まだこれを―
過去にメールが送れる
マシンとは言えないわ
really sends messages to the past.
Before we continue,
先に進む前に
今あるものの解明が先よ
we should deal with more relevant issues first.
Boring!
つまらん
99.9% of science is boring.
科学なんて99％は
つまらないものの積み重ね
If you call yourself a scientist...
あんたも科学者を
自称するなら…
I'm not a scientist!
（岡部）科学者ではない！
I'm a mad scientist!
マッドサイエンティストだと
言ってるだろうが！
Epic fail. I better do something soon.
ダメだ こいつ
早くなんとかしないと
（まゆり）ん？
（橋田）おお 牧瀬氏？
Miss Makise...
あっ？
Don't tell me you're...
貴様 まさか…
Shut up!
（紅莉栖）うるさい！
それ以上 言うな
Not another word!
Because that's impossible!
そんなわけないから！
は… 早く
話を進めなさいよ
Get back on topic already.
Continuing on to the reports.
では 続いて報告に移る
How's the translation of SERN's server documents going, Christina?
ＳＥＲＮサーバー内にあった―
データの翻訳状況は
どうなっている？
クリスティーナ もとい―
Or should I say,
ねらーよ
4channer?
I told you that's not true!
だから違うって言ってんだろ
Then you sure know your memes.
（岡部）…の割にはＩＤ真っ赤に
I do not!
してない！
There's nothing to report.
と… 特に
報告することはないわ
I see.
（岡部）そうか
引き続き調査を頼む
Continue your investigations...
ねらーよ
4channer!
Stop calling me that!
“ねらー”って言うな！
次にダル
ハッキングの状況は？
Daru's up next. How's the hacking coming?
No change.
（橋田）変わりない
Until I analyze the mysterious program on the other server, there'll probably be no change.
別サーバにある
謎のプログラムを解析しないと―
状況は変わらないと思われ…
How's the IBN 5100 analysis going?
（岡部）
ＩＢＮ5100での解析は？
It'd be great if I could do it.
（橋田）それができれば
言うことなしなんだが
え？ どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
Huh?
どういうこと？
You haven't started the analysis?
まだ解析をしていない
ということか？
（岡部）あ？ どうやってやるん？
How would I do that?
ハッ
Where's the IBN 5100?
ＩＢＮ5100は どこにある？
How would I know?
僕が知るわけないっしょ
That can't be...
（岡部）まさか！
ああっ！
Okarin, what's wrong?
（まゆり）オカリン どうしたの？
Christina...
（岡部）クリスティーナ…
did I, by any chance, fail to find the IBN 5100?
もしかして俺は―
ＩＢＮ5100を
見つけていないのか？
You don't even know where it is.
もしかしても何も―
どこにあるかも
分かってないじゃない
I see.
（紅莉栖）なるほどね
So if I choose to believe what you say, you found the IBN 5100.
仮に その話を信じるとしたら―
岡部はＩＢＮ5100を見つけた
Yes.
（岡部）ああ
I carried it back here with you.
お前と一緒に
ここまで運んできた
But you're the only one with any memory of that.
（紅莉栖）けど その記憶は
岡部以外の誰にも残っていない
The D-mails probably changed the past.
恐らくＤメールによる
過去改変ね
だっ！ 過去改変？
Changed the past...
But we've only sent minor stuff.
しかし 送った内容は
ささいなものばかりだぞ
It's the butterfly effect.
バタフライエフェクトよ
Sending one message into the past
（紅莉栖）
過去に１つのメールを
送ることで
causes the world line to split,
そこから世界線は分岐する
from a world where we didn't buy a Lotto 6 ticket
ロト６(シックス)を買わなかった世界から
買った世界へ
to one where we did.
Little by little, this changes what was meant to happen.
それによって
あったはずの出来事や事実が―
少しずつ変わっていく
One change causes another,
１つの変化は―
and they pile on top of one another.
玉突きのように
次の変化を起こし―
それは次第に
大きくなっていく
It's one of the long-recognized risks of altering the past.
（紅莉栖）
昔から よくいわれている
過去改変のリスクの１つよ
（岡部）
では ＩＢＮ5100は どこに？
Then where is the IBN 5100?
Let me ask this instead:
逆に聞く
どこにあったの？
where was it?
ハッ
Yes, when I asked my dad, he said it used to be here, but...
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）はい
ええ お父さんに聞いたら―
確かに奉納されていると
いうのですが…
It's gone now.
今は どこにも…
（岡部）そうか
I see.
Well?
（紅莉栖）どうだった？
確かに
柳林(やなばやし)神社にＩＢＮ5100はあった
There was an IBN 5100 at Yanabayashi Shrine,
but it's gone now.
…が 現在はない
No one knows when it was taken or by whom.
誰が いつ持ち出したのかも
分からない
A dead end, huh?
行き止まりか…
But it's strange to donate a PC to a shrine.
でも神社に
パソコンを奉納するなんて―
不思議だねえ
I wonder who would do that.
誰が そんなことしたんだろう
ハッ
（フェイリス）フウ…
（メイド）
フェイリスちゃん
Feyris?
What's up?
（フェイリス）ニャンニャン？
Here's the list of ten questions I wrote
（メイド）今度のイベントの
メイドさんへの10の質問―
to ask the maids at the next event.
これにしようと思うんだけど
Let me see...
どーれどれ？
ああ…
"If you could go back and redo one thing from your past, what would it be?"
“過去に戻って１つだけ
やり直せるとしたら―”
“何をしますか？”
What would you do, Feyris?
（メイド）
フェイリスちゃんは何する？
ええ？
ああ そうだニャ
フェイリスは…
Let me think...
Feyris... doesn't look back on her past!
過去は振り返らないニャ
It's the task of the cat-eared maid who brings everyone happiness, to forge ahead!
前を向いて歩いていくのが―
みんなに幸せを届ける
ネコミミメイドの使命ニャ
わあっ！
あっ 電話 電話っと…
Oh, my phone!
Hi, this is Feyris.
はい フェイリスニャ
ん！ 凶真？
Kyouma.
ニャ パソコン？
A PC?
An IBN 5100.
（岡部）ＩＢＮ5100だ
Did your family give it to Yanabayashi Shrine?
柳林神社に奉納したという
事実はあるか？
（フェイリス）ニャア～
よく覚えてニャいけど
I don't really remember...
But my daddy did have a lot of old PCs.
パパが古いパソコンを
たくさん持っていたのは確かニャ
Kyouma.
凶真…
Is this related to the time machine
それは さっき言ってた
タイムマシンと―
you were talking about?
何か関係があるニャ？
（まゆり）わあ 見て見て
Look, look!
It's an Upa!
うーぱ メタルうーぱだよ
A metal Upa!
Do you still want a metal Upa?
やはり メタルうーぱが
欲しいのか？
（まゆり）あ… やはり？
Still?
How long are you going to stand there staring at it? Let's go.
何分 ここにいるつもりだ？
もう行くぞ
あ… 待ってよ
Wait!
Daru!
ダル君
Sorry to make you wait!
（橋田）お待たせしますた
（岡部）ん？
ああっ
What did you buy now?
何を買ってるんだ！
いやあ 瞬殺だった
限定版 見つけたん
I found a limited-edition that sold out before I could buy it!
As you might say,
オカリン風に言うと―
"This encounter was the choice of Steins Gate!"
この巡り会い
まさにシュタインズ･ゲートの選択
軽々しく使うな！
Don't use it for stuff like this!
Anyway, why are you two following me?
大体 お前たち
なぜ ついてくるのだ
You could've stayed back at the lab with the assistant.
助手と一緒に
留守番していればいいだろう
Once I heard you were going to Feyris's place,
フェイリスたんの自宅と
聞いたら―
I had to come along!
凸(とつ)せざるを得ないだろう 常考(じょうこう)
まゆしぃだって遊び行きたいよ
I wanted to go and play too!
ハア… フェイリスのやつ
どうして自宅に来いなどと…
Why did Feyris tell me to come to her house?
It's Kirari!
（まゆり）あっ！ キラリちゃんだ
あっ まゆり おいっ！
Mayuri, wait...
Geez...
まったく…
The IBN 5100.
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）ＩＢＮ5100…
（岡部）ハッ
Shining Finger!
（岡部）
シャイニング･フィンガー
Wait! Hey!
待てっ おい！
（クラクション）
（岡部）ちっ
Shining...
シャイニング！
Moeka!
萌郁
Kiryuu Moeka!
桐生萌郁！
（クラクション）
あっ ああ
ハア ハア…
あっ ああ…
Why?
（萌郁）どうして…
FB said it was there!
ＦＢはあるって言ってたのに…
Okabe...
岡部君？
Back there, you mentioned the IBN 5100...
さっきＩＢＮ5100と…
Do you know where it is?
（萌郁）知ってるの？
どこにあるのか？
You don't know either?
お前も… 知らないのか？
I don't.
知ら… ないの？
Okarin!
（まゆり）オカリーン
あ… 萌郁さん？
Moeka?
ああ…
Yeah.
Okarin...
（橋田）オカリン
Moeka's so pretty and stylish.
（まゆり）萌郁さん
キレイでスタイル抜群だなあ
I'm sure she'd make a great cosplayer.
コスプレしたら
きっと映えそうだよ
（岡部）ああ
Mayuri, you know Shining Finger?
まゆり
お前 シャイニング･フィンガーの
ことを知っているのか？
え？ 知ってるよ
I do!
How?
なぜだ なぜ知ってる？
How do you know her?
You brought her to the lab!
オカリンが連れてきたよ～
ぬおっ
After Moeka sent her D-mail,
（岡部）
萌郁がＤメールを送ったあと
she disappeared from everyone's memory.
萌郁の存在は
みんなの記憶から消えた
And then, after Ruka sent his D-mail,
そして るかがＤメールを
送ったあとには―
they knew her again.
再び萌郁を
知ってる状態になっていた
Little by little, the world changes
メールによる過去改変が
起きるたびに―
each time a D-mail is sent to the past?
事実が少しずつ
変化しているのか？
Is this really the place?
（岡部）本当にここなのか？
I'm sure of it.
（まゆり）間違いないよ
えっと… 一番上みたい
Seems it's on the top floor.
The mistress will be here soon.
（執事）お嬢様は
もうまもなく参ります
Just one moment.
お待ちください
Butler cafés aren't my thing.
僕 執事喫茶のほうは
ちょっと趣味じゃないのだが
A real butler!
本物だよ　初めて見た
I've never seen one before.
フッ ハハハハッ
Look!
見ろ！ 人がゴミのようだ！
Everyone looks like ants!
I love it!
いい眺めだ！
フゥ ハハハハッ
Okarin...
（まゆり）オカリン…
Figures he'd say that.
（橋田）言うと思った
Sorry for the wait.
（フェイリス）
お待たせしたニャ
Oh, Feyris!
ああ フェリスちゃん
うおおっ
Now it's Feyris wearing her normal clothes!
今度はフェイリスたんの私服
What luck!
なんたる僥倖(ぎょうこう)
ハア ハア…
Feyris Meow Meow!
（岡部）
フェイリスニャンニャン
It seems I must question your true identity!
どうやら お前の正体を―
聞いておかねば
ならないようだな
フェイリスは…
Feyris is...
...Feyris, meow!
フェイリス ニャン！
Stop fooling around!
（岡部）ふざけるな！
If you refuse to explain, then I'm leaving!
説明がないのなら
帰らせてもらう
Oh, fine.
しかたがないニャア
Feyris's family owns all the land around here!
フェイリスの家は
ここら辺の―
大地主だったんだニャ
じゃあ もしかして
アキバって…
Then Akiba is...
That's right.
（フェイリス）
うん そういうことニャ
え？ アキバがどうしたん？
What about Akiba now?
It's Feyris's real name.
（まゆり）
フェリスちゃんの本名だよ
Akiha Rumiho!
秋葉留未穂(あきはるみほ)ちゃんって
いうんだよ
あー あー あー！
聞こえない
I didn't hear that!
Feyris's real name is Feyris!
フェイリスたんの本名は
フェイリスたん！
What a sad attempt to escape reality.
見苦しい現実逃避だな
By the way, Feyris was the one
ちなみにアキバに萌(も)え文化を
取り入れるように―
who asked to bring the culture of cute to Akiba.
お願いしたのは
フェイリスなのニャン
（岡部）なっ そこまで
No way!
And she works as an angel at May Queen
（橋田）そして自らも
天使として「メイクイーン」で―
to further spread the culture of cute!
萌え文化の浸透に
努めているなんて
How splendid!
なんて神！
And my eyes are also splendid for recognizing her before anyone else!
そんな神にいち早く注目した
僕の目も神
But, but... keep it a secret, okay?
でもでも 今の話は―
ないしょにしておいて
ほしいニャン
I want you to treat me with Feyris-love, just like you always have!
みんなも 今までどおり
フェイリスラブで―
接してほしいニャ
I will! Totally!
接します！ 全力で！
Thank you, meow-meow!
（フェイリス）
ありがとニャンニャン
No meow-meows!
“ニャンニャン”ではない！
Anyway, what about the IBN 5100?
それより
ＩＢＮ5100についてだ
Oh, that?
ああ そのことニャ？
でも その前に
簡単なお願いがあるんだけど～
But before that, I have a simple request...
You want to arrange a trade?
（岡部）
貴様 取り引きしようというのか！
It's nothing difficult.
そんなに
難しいことじゃないニャ
ただ 一度だけＤメールを
使わせてほしいだけニャ
I only want you to let me use the D-mail, just once.
（岡部）ぬおっ
（橋田）お安い御用だお
Of course!
Use it as much as you want!
一度と言わず何度でも…
Wait! The D-mail is absolutely off-limits to outsiders...
待て！
Ｄメールは部外者には
絶対秘密の…
Then why not make Feyris a lab member too?
だったら
フェリスちゃんも―
ラボメンになれば
いいんじゃないかなあ？
Wait! Wait!
（岡部）いや 待て 待つのだ！
Sending more messages to the past would be—
これ以上
Ｄメールを送るのは…
なっ 私利私欲で―
You're the one who sent the Lotto 6 number back to try and make money,
ロト６当てようとして
メール出しておいて！
yet you won't send one for Feyris?
フェイリスたんはダメだと？
Just this once!
（まゆり）１回だけだよお
いや そういうことではなく
No, that's not it...
But if I stop now,
（岡部）しかし
ここでやめたところで
there's no guarantee that the IBN 5100 will return.
ＩＢＮ5100が戻ってくる
保証はない
If this is any indication...
少しでも手がかりに
つながるなら…
分かった
Very well.
But as Mayuri said,
ただし
まゆりも言ったように―
you'll have to become a lab member.
フェイリスには
ラボメンになってもらう
You are now Lab Member 007,
お前は今日から―
ラボメンメンバー００７
秋葉留未…
Akiha Ru—
I-I-I can't hear you!
あー あー
き… 聞こえない
It's done.
出来たニャ
You're sure you want to send it back ten years, right?
本当に送るのは
10年前でいいんだな？
I'm sure!
間違いないニャ
What does it say?
メールの内容は？
あっ それは…
Well... it's a secret!
秘密だニャ
Tell me.
そういうわけには いかない
As leader of the lab, it's my job to know.
俺にはラボのリーダーとして
その内容を知っておく義務が…
ダメニャ
No. A maiden's private life is off-limits to guys.
乙女のプライベートは
男子禁制ニャ
I think it's wrong to look at someone's emails.
人のメール見るのは
よくないと思います
I agree! Totally!
激しく同意！
What?
なっ！
くっ…
Fine.
しかたないか
Then put your hand on the send button and wait.
では送信ボタンに
手を置いて待て
Hello?
（紅莉栖）ハロー
It's me!
（岡部）俺だあ
そちらの状況を伝えろ…
What's the situation...
She hung up on me, dammit!
（岡部）あの女 切りやがった
Yeah, I bet she did.
（橋田）そりゃ 切られるっしょ
（岡部）
クリスティーナめ
助手の分際で
That Christina!
Doesn't she know she's my assistant?
（紅莉栖）ハロー
Hello?
It's Hououin Kyouma. Don't just hang up on me without a word.
鳳凰院凶真だ
無言で切るな
Hououin?
（紅莉栖）鳳凰院？
Oh, Okabe.
なんだ岡部か
いたずら電話かと思った
I thought it was a prank call.
I'm sure you saw my number on the display.
（岡部）こちらの番号は
表示されていただろう
Even so, those first words
（紅莉栖）それでも いきなり
あんなこと言われたら
were creepy enough to make me hang up.
気味悪くなって切るわよ
（岡部）フッフフ
In other words, you are terrified of the mighty Hououin Kyouma—
それはつまり
この鳳凰院凶真に畏怖を―
（岡部）覚えていると あ…
She hung up on me! She hung up on me again!
あいつ また切った
また切ったぞ
Okarin, aren't you ready yet?
（まゆり）オカリン まだ？
Wait!
待て
あの冷血放蕩(ほうとう)天才変態少女め
Curse you, cold-blooded pervert girl genius...
Hello?
（紅莉栖）ハロー
（岡部）聞け！
Listen, the Zomb—
（岡部）ザ･ゾン…
（紅莉栖）ハロー
Hello?
Hello, my name is Okabe Rintarou.
（岡部）わ… 私
岡部倫太郎と申しますが
（紅莉栖）何？
What is it?
I would be eternally grateful
（岡部）
「電話レンジ（仮）(かっこかり)」の設定を―
if you'd set the Phone Microwave (name subject to change)
先ほど
お送りさせていただいた―
おメールのとおりに
お設定して―
to the values I proffered in my earlier message.
お起動していただきたく
思うのですが…
You should have just said that from the start.
（紅莉栖）最初から
そう言えばいいのよ
Also, that isn't what "proffer" means.
それと敬語 変だから
You're embarrassing yourself.
日本人として
それじゃあ恥ずかしいわよ
And stop calling it the Phone Microwave (name subject to change) already.
あと 電話レンジの
“（仮）”っていうのも…
（岡部）だーっ！
黙れ このセレセブが！
Shut up, Cel 7!
I'm trying to be polite, and you're...
下手(したて)に出れば
いい気になりおって！
Do they not like each other?
仲が悪いのかニャ？
I think it's the opposite.
多分 いいんじゃないかなあ
Agreed.
まゆ氏に同意
（フェイリス）ん…
Will you send?
Maybe...
やっぱり…
（まゆり）うん？
Maybe...
やっぱり
メールはしなくても…
Maybe I don't need to do this.
Feyris!
（岡部）フェイリス
（フェイリス）あっ…
The electricity's started.
放電が始まった　送信しろ
Send it.
（岡部）ううっ
うう… うっ
お…
あ…
あの…
Um...
（秋葉幸高(ゆきたか)）ん？
Who are you?
（岡部）あなたは？
はあ？
え…
（フェイリス）パパ！
Daddy!
Daddy?
パパ？
Were you talking to Kyouma?
凶真と話していたのかニャ？
Yeah.
ああ
I'll be on my way.
では 私はこれで
Enjoy yourselves.
どうぞ ごゆっくり
フェリスちゃんの
お父さんって―
Feyris's dad has this kind of refined air about him, doesn't he?
なんか気品があるねえ
Indeed! You can tell he's Feyris's dad.
さすがフェイリスたんの
父君を名乗るだけはある
（岡部）あの…
Um...
（秋葉）ん？
Do you know anything about an IBN 5100?
ＩＢＮ5100をご存じですか？
（秋葉）んん…
I haven't heard that name in ages.
ずいぶん
懐かしい名前ですね
探しているんです
I'm looking for one.
Unfortunately, I parted with mine a long time ago.
（秋葉）残念ですが―
もうずいぶん前に
手放してしまいまして
Did you give it to Yanabayashi Shrine?
もしかして柳林神社に
奉納されたとか
（秋葉）神社？
Shrine?
No, I didn't.
いえ そのようなことは
Goodbye, then.
では 失礼
Before Feyris sent her D-mail,
（岡部）フェイリスが
Ｄメールを送る前
I heard that the IBN 5100 disappeared after it had been given to Yanabayashi Shrine.
ＩＢＮ5100は
神社に奉納されたあと消えた
But now, the shrine never got it.
…が 今度は そもそも
奉納されていない
Each time we send a message, things change.
メールを送るたびに
何かが少しずつ変わっていく
Something may be changing,
俺の知らないところでも―
even without me being aware of it.
何かが変わっているの
かもしれない
It's possible that we've already done something that can't be undone.
kisei sareta chikai mujihi naru, juuni no shinri nogarerarenai
We cannot escape the 12 merciless truths and the controlled oath we took
Okarin! Okarin!
Mayushii is going to Nakano to buy a Lovely Sword comic.
Lovely Sword?
Kouga Yui?
Nakano's far away.
Yeah.
I wish there was a Toranoana comic shop here.
ansoku no asu wo negattara
If we wish for a tomorrow full of rest
What are you talking about?
Toranoana's right over there.
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
to be given to the precious event horizon in our hands
What are you talking about, Okarin?
Why would there be one in Akiba?
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
In the promise we made in captivity appeared the contours of a lie
（岡部）もしかしたら
俺たちは もう―
取り返しの
つかないことを…
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
The realm of life recorded a time of blindness
（まゆり）
オカリン オカリン
まゆしぃは―
哀(あい)ソードの
同人誌 買いに―
中野(なかの)に寄るので
帰ります
（橋田）哀ソード？
甲賀(こうが)ゆいかあ
habatake butterfly
Fly, butterfly
中野とは―
ずいぶん
遠回りするのだな
kiseki no butterfly
O, miraculous butterfly
（まゆり）うん
「とらのあな」―
anata he sasagu
I will sacrifice to you
こっちのほうにも
あればいいのになあ
あっ 何を
言っているのだ
namida no butterfly
Butterflies of tears
「とらのあな」なら
そこに…
mabushii butterfly
Dazzling butterflies
え？
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
Everything is being rewritten
（まゆり）オカリン
何 言ってるの？
（橋田）アキバに
あるわけないっしょ
～